Chris Scharf

Web Application Developer at Igicom

scharfie@gmail.com

Summary

I've had a love of programming ever since I was young, when I would spent countless hours trying out new ideas. Coupled now with all my experience, I'm very comfortable tackling new problems, troubleshooting and crafting elegant solutions. I learn fast, work hard, and strive for beautiful, testable code.

Experience

Web Application Developer at Igicom

March 2008 - Present (7 years 5 months)

Web application architecture and development, server management, front-end development.

Web Application Developer at West Virginia University

December 2004 - March 2008 (3 years 4 months)

Developed multi-site content management system.

Resident Network Consultant at West Virginia University

August 2001 - December 2004 (3 years 5 months)

Consulted incoming students on computer purchases, performed network connection checks once a year, and removed lots and lots of spyware & viruses from student machines :-)

Resident Network Consultant at WVU

2001 - 2004 (3 years)

Repaired software- and hardware-related problems with student machines, consulted on computer purchasing to incoming students.

Skills & Expertise

Ruby on Rails

Ruby

Web Development

HTML

JavaScript

jQuery

User Experience

CSS

PHP

WordPress

Information Architecture
Web Applications
User Interface Design
MySQL
AJAX
Web Analytics
Web Project Management
HTML 5
Mobile Applications

Agile Project Management

Projects

UnionPlus

December 2008 to Present

Members: Chris Scharf

Lead developer in charge of all back-end code, administrative tools, and some front-end code.

Marmalade Skies

November 2013 to Present

Members: Chris Scharf

Lead developer in charge of all front-end and back-end code as well as server setup and maintenance.

Frommer's

November 2013 to Present

Members: Chris Scharf

Education

West Virginia University

BS, Computer Engineering, 2001 - 2005

Interests

programming, music, gaming, science

Chris Scharf

Web Application Developer at Igicom

scharfie@gmail.com



Contact Chris on LinkedIn